<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>O5wald</title><link>https://o5wald.github.io/</link><description>Learn Share Grow</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://o5wald.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple Keylogger for Windows</title><link>https://o5wald.github.io/posts/keylogger/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://o5wald.github.io/posts/keylogger/</guid><description>Simple Keylogger for Windows Very important note:
This Program To be used for educational use and not for malicious tasks! I will NOT be held responsible for anything silly you may do with this! What is Keylogger ? keylogger is application or a program that record the keys pressed by user and store into file Program:
NOTE: we are writing simple demonstration program in which we using fucntion called kbhit() to detect if any key is pressed on keyboard.</description></item><item><title>Client-Server Chat Room using Python</title><link>https://o5wald.github.io/posts/2021-11-17-client-server-chatroom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://o5wald.github.io/posts/2021-11-17-client-server-chatroom/</guid><description>Client-Server Chat Room In my previous article, I covered what a socket is and the different types of sockets, as well as the C implementation. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll use Sockets to create a client-server chat room in Python.
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at how client-server architecture works first. The client-server architecture is a model in which the server hosts, provides, and controls the majority of the resources and services that the client consumes. One or more client computers are connected to a central server through a network or the internet in this architecture.</description></item><item><title>Socket Programming 101 using C</title><link>https://o5wald.github.io/posts/socket-prog-101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://o5wald.github.io/posts/socket-prog-101/</guid><description>Socket Programming 101 What is socket? Socket is one endpoint of a communication link between systems. Your application sends and receives all of its network data through a socket.
There are few different socket application programming interfaces (APIs).
Berkeley Sockets released in 1983 with 4.3BSD Unix. The terms Berkeley sockets, BSD sockets, Unix sockets, and Portable Operating System Interface (POSIX) sockets are often used interchangeably If you&amp;rsquo;re using Linux or macOS, then your operating system provides a proper implementation of Berkeley sockets.</description></item><item><title>Networking Basics</title><link>https://o5wald.github.io/posts/networking_basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://o5wald.github.io/posts/networking_basics/</guid><description>Topics Coverd: Netwrok Programming and C OSI and TCP/IP The Internet Protocol IPv4 and IPv6 Domain Names Internet Protocol routing Network Address translation some more Topics The internet and C millions of desktops, laptops,routers and servers conneted to the internet and have been for decades. the new Internet of Things(IoT) trend atracting peoples to use and learn Networking. Almost every network stack is programmed in C. This is true for Windows, Linux, and macOS.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://o5wald.github.io/posts/binary_exploitation_basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://o5wald.github.io/posts/binary_exploitation_basics/</guid><description>Basics for Binary Exploitation we all know how C programs is get compiled.
first your C file goes to the compiler, then compiler convert it into sequence of operation that will be executed by computer each operation compiled into sequence of bytes called operation code or OP code Why Assembly ? trying to read the instruction that our computer executing is impossible. Assembly is Language that designed for translating the instruction that our computer will execute into human readable language.</description></item></channel></rss>